<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language id="44">
  
  <!-- GalaxyTrader MK3 AI Order -->
  <page id="77000" title="GalaxyTrader MK3" descr="GalaxyTrader MK3 Localization" voice="no">
    <!-- Order Names -->
    <t id="10001">Dock and Wait (GalaxyTrader MK3)</t>
    <t id="10002">GalaxyTrader MK3</t>
    <t id="10003">Final Examination (GalaxyTrader MK3)</t>
    <t id="10004">Pilot Exchange Rendezvous</t>
    <t id="10005">GalaxyTrader MK4 Supply</t>
    <t id="10006">Return Home</t>
    
    <!-- Order Descriptions -->
    <t id="10101">Dock at station and wait for specified duration</t>
    <t id="10102">Autonomous trading with skill progression</t>
    <t id="10103">Take final examination for pilot certification at training facility</t>
    <t id="10104">Dock at rendezvous station for pilot exchange</t>
    <t id="10105">Supply-focused trading for player stations using cache and live search</t>
    <t id="10106">Dock at home station and remain there until trading resumes</t>
    
    <!-- Trade Order Names -->
    <t id="10201">Buy %s from %s</t>
    <t id="10202">Sell %s to %s</t>
    <t id="10203">Trade with %s</t>
    <t id="1000">{77000,10002}</t>
    <t id="1001">Advanced trading system with XP progression and fleet coordination</t>
    <t id="1002">Home Base</t>
    <t id="1003">Use presets</t>
    <t id="1004">Trade all wares</t>
    <t id="1005">Trade legal wares</t>
    <t id="1006">Trade illegal wares</t>
    <t id="1007">Enable XP progression</t>
    <t id="1008">Enable fleet coordination</t>
    <t id="1009">Enable market analysis</t>
    <t id="1010">Enable territory management</t>
    
    <!-- Order Parameter Names -->
    <t id="1011">Allow Illegal Wares</t>
    <t id="1012">Logbook Entries</t>
    <t id="1013">Risk Tolerance</t>
    <t id="1014">Prioritize Player Stations</t>
    <t id="1015">Auto Wares</t>
    <t id="1016">Distance Penalty %</t>
    <t id="1017">Notification Level</t>
    <t id="1018">Fleet Coordination</t>
    <t id="1019">Cargo Fill Target %</t>
    <t id="1050">Market Update Frequency</t>
    <t id="1051">Trade Evaluation Logging</t>
    <t id="1052">Sector Whitelist</t>
    <t id="1054">Ignore Carrier/Aux Ships</t>
    <t id="1056">Ignore Build Storage</t>
    <t id="1058">Ignore Trade Rules</t>
    <t id="1060">Ignore MK1-Supplied Stations</t>
    <t id="1063">Under development</t>
    <t id="1064">Priority Wares</t>
    <t id="1065">Priority Score %</t>
    <t id="1066">Wares to favor in trade scoring. Their score is multiplied by Priority Score %.</t>
    <t id="1067">Score multiplier for Priority Wares: 125%=+25% min, 150%=+50%%, 200%=2x, 300%=3x. Applied last.</t>
    <t id="1068">── Priority Ware Filter ──</t>
    <t id="1069">Wares (Manual)</t>
    <t id="1070">Illegal Route Filter</t>
    <t id="1072">Serve Home Only</t>
    <t id="1073">Buy from Player</t>
    <t id="1074">Buy from Factions</t>
    <t id="1075">Include Build Storage</t>
    <t id="1076">Include Resources</t>
    <t id="1077">Include Intermediates</t>
    <t id="1078">Include Tradewares</t>
    <t id="1080">Max Trades per Cycle</t>
    <t id="1081">Backtrack Tolerance</t>
    <t id="1082">Min Cargo Used %</t>
    <t id="1083">Player Buy Modifier %</t>
    <t id="1085">Assign to Home Station</t>
    <t id="1086">Coverage Distance</t>
    <t id="1088">Maximum jump distance from home for demand coverage</t>
    <t id="1090">Include tradeware-class wares in demand/supply matching</t>
    <t id="1091">Modifier applied to player-owned supplier pricing in scoring-only calculations</t>
    
    <!-- Ship Name Status Prefixes -->
    <t id="7001">[ADVANCE]</t>
    <t id="7002">[TRAINING]</t>
    <t id="7008">[FALLBACK]</t>
    <t id="7009">[ISOLATED]</t>
    
    <!-- Ship Name Operational State Prefixes -->
    <t id="7003">[REPAIR]</t>
    <t id="7004">[RESUPPLY]</t>
    <t id="7005">[MAINTENANCE]</t>
    <t id="7006">[REROUTE]</t>
    <t id="7007">[CLEARANCE]</t>
    
    <!-- Parameter Tooltips -->
    <t id="1020">Choose home sector or station where trader operates</t>
    <t id="1021">Maximum jump gate distance when buying wares (limited by pilot skill)</t>
    <t id="1022">Maximum jump gate distance when selling wares (limited by pilot skill)</t>
    <t id="1023">Automatic selection of suitable wares based on category</t>
    <t id="1024">Manual selection of specific trading wares</t>
    <t id="1025">Allow trading in contraband and illegal goods</t>
    <t id="1026">Security tolerance: 0.0=Only safe sectors, 1.0=Accept all risks</t>
    <t id="1027">Improve pilot skills through trading experience</t>
    <t id="1028">Automatically send pilots for training when needed</t>
    <t id="1029">Coordinate multiple trading ships to avoid conflicts</t>
    <t id="1030">Ware focus: 0=Balanced, 1=Advanced, 2=Basic needs, 3=Illegal, 4=Bulk goods</t>
    <t id="1031">Trading area: 0=Balanced, 1=Home focus, 2=Free roam</t>
    <t id="1032">Notification level: 0=Minimal, 1=Normal, 2=Detailed messages</t>
    <t id="1033">Target cargo utilization percentage before prioritizing sales</t>
    <t id="1034">How often market data and price information is updated</t>
    <t id="1035">Debug output level: 0=None, 1=Basic, 2=Verbose logging</t>
    <t id="1036">Share profitable trade routes with fleet (cached for quick access)</t>
    <t id="1037">Minimum profit required to cache trade and share with fleet</t>
    <t id="1038">Maximum profit decline allowed before cached trade routes become invalid</t>
    <t id="1039">How long cached trade routes remain valid before expiring</t>
    <t id="1040">Enable detailed logging of individual trade evaluations and rejections (can be very verbose)</t>
    <t id="1041">Enable per-trade logbook entries and immersive training messages (TaterTrader style)</t>
    <t id="1053">Sectors in this list are excluded from blacklists (always allowed)</t>
    <t id="1055">Exclude carriers and auxiliary ships from trading</t>
    <t id="1057">Exclude build storage ships from trading</t>
    <t id="1059">Ignore station trade rules during offer search (advanced; may select offers normally blocked)</t>
    <t id="1061">Skip player stations that have an MK1 trader with Supply mode assigned</t>
    <t id="1062">Boost trade scores for routes involving your own stations (10% score bonus)</t>
    <t id="1071">When Allow Illegal Wares is enabled, only trade illegal wares if legal in all sectors on the jump path (buy, sell, and intermediate sectors).</t>
    <t id="1087">Maximum jump distance from home for supplier purchase search</t>
    <t id="1089">When disabled, ship can supply stations in coverage area by urgency priority instead of home-only mode</t>
    
    <!-- XP and Training Messages -->
    <t id="2000">%s has gained %s XP!</t>
    <t id="2001">%s has leveled up! New level: %s</t>
    <t id="2002">%s needs training! Please send to nearest shipyard or trading station.</t>
    <t id="2003">%s has started training at %s</t>
    <t id="2004">%s has completed training and is now certified for level %s!</t>
    <t id="2005">%s reached Skill Level %s after training! XP progression unlocked at %s.</t>
    <t id="2006">%s reached Skill Level %s from %s trade!</t>
    <t id="2007">%s completed Level %s training! XP progression unlocked at %s.</t>
    
    <!-- Trade Messages -->
    <t id="3000">%s has completed a trade! Profit: %s Cr</t>
    <t id="3001">%s is analyzing market conditions...</t>
    <t id="3002">%s has found a profitable trade route!</t>
    <t id="3003">No profitable trade routes available for %s</t>
    
    <!-- Per-Trade Logbook Messages (TaterTrader style) -->
    <t id="3100">Selling %1 %2 from cargo at %3. I should earn %4 in profit.</t>
    <t id="3101">Queuing up trade order for %1 %2. Buying at %3 to sell at %4. I should earn %5 in profit.</t>
    <t id="3102">Station Trader: Supplying %1 %2 from %3 to %4.</t>
    <t id="3103">Station Trader: Selling %1 %2 at the price of %3. Expected profit is %4.</t>
    <t id="3104">Trade completed successfully for %1 %2. Total profit: %3 Credits.</t>
    <t id="3105">Trade route cached: %1 %2 from %3 to %4 (Profit: %5 Cr)</t>
    <t id="3106">\nTotal estimated lifetime profit before this trade: %1 Cr.</t>
    <t id="3107">Queuing up multitrade: %1. I should earn %2 in profit.</t>
    <t id="3120">Pilot Transfer Initiated</t>
    <t id="3121">Transfer protocol acknowledged. %1 (%2) and %3 (%4) are proceeding to %5 (%6) to dock and exchange command seats.</t>
    
    <!-- Training Messages (Immersive/Roleplay Style) -->
    <t id="3200">Hello Commander %1,\n\nI have gained enough experience to take my certification exam for the title "%2". The examination will take approximately %3 minutes at %4.\n\nThis is an important milestone in my career development. The exam will test my knowledge of advanced trading protocols, market analysis, and fleet coordination procedures.\n\nI'm confident in my abilities and excited to prove myself worthy of this advancement. Wish me luck!\n\nRespectfully,\n%5\nAboard %6</t>
    <t id="3201">Commander %1,\n\nExcellent news! I have successfully completed my certification examination and earned the title "%2"!\n\nThe examination covered advanced trading strategies, risk assessment protocols, and fleet coordination procedures. I'm pleased to report that I passed with distinction.\n\nI'm now qualified to handle more complex trading operations and look forward to contributing even more to our fleet's success. Thank you for investing in my professional development.\n\nWith renewed dedication,\n%3\nCertified %2\nAboard %4</t>
    <t id="3202">Commander %1,\n\nI regret to inform you that my certification exam was interrupted due to operational requirements. I will need to reschedule when circumstances permit.\n\nI remain committed to advancing my skills and will notify you when I can resume the examination process.\n\nRespectfully,\n%2\nAboard %3</t>
    <t id="3203">Commander %1,\n\nI am currently en route to %2 for my certification examination. The journey gives me time to review my studies and prepare mentally for this important step in my career.\n\nExpected arrival: %3 minutes\nExamination duration: %4 minutes\n\nI appreciate your confidence in my abilities and the opportunity for advancement.\n\nWith determination,\n%5\nAboard %6</t>
    
    <!-- Cargo Safety and Maintenance Messages (Roleplay Style) -->
    <t id="3204">Commander,\n\nI've detected cargo in my hold during my systems check. Before I can begin normal trading operations, I need to sell this merchandise.\n\nI'm using our trade search to find the best buyer and safely offload this cargo. Once my hold is clear, I'll proceed with automated trading.\n\nStatus: Searching for optimal sale location\n\nWith diligence,\nAboard %1</t>
    <t id="3205">Commander,\n\nMy hull integrity has dropped to %1%% (threshold: %2%%). As a Level %3 pilot, I'm authorized to request auto-repair services.\n\nI'm proceeding to %4 for repair work. The estimated cost is %5 Cr, which is within our budget.\n\nOnce repairs are complete, I'll resume trading operations with full structural integrity.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %6</t>
    <t id="3206">Commander,\n\nURGENT FINANCIAL WARNING\n\nMy hull integrity is critical at %1%% (threshold: %2%%), but our available funds (%3 Cr) are insufficient for full repairs (estimated cost: %4 Cr).\n\nI'm proceeding to %5 for PARTIAL REPAIRS using our available funds. This isn't an ideal solution, but it's necessary to maintain operational capability.\n\nPlease consider allocating additional funds for future maintenance operations.\n\nConcerned but determined,\nAboard %6</t>
    <t id="3207">Commander,\n\nMy Level %1 certification authorizes automatic resupply of defensive equipment. After checking my systems, I've determined that my countermeasures and deployables are below recommended thresholds.\n\nI'm proceeding to %2 to restock my defensive equipment:\n• Countermeasures: Replenishing to optimal capacity\n• Defense drones, trade drones, laser towers: Applying balance profile\n\nThis resupply ensures I'm best protected against space threats while maintaining trading efficiency.\n\nWith vigilance,\nAboard %3</t>
    <t id="3212">Commander,\n\nMy hull integrity has dropped to %1%% (threshold: %2%%), and I need repair services. However, the nearest repair station at %3 is currently unreachable due to sector travel restrictions (blacklisted routes).\n\nI will continue with trading operations despite this limitation. Once safe routes become available again, I will automatically seek repair services.\n\nI will monitor the situation and notify you when repairs become possible.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %4</t>
    <t id="3213">Commander,\n\nMy defensive equipment requires resupply, but the nearest equipment station at %1 is currently unreachable due to sector travel restrictions (blacklisted routes).\n\nI will continue with trading operations despite this limitation. Once safe routes become available again, I will automatically seek resupply services.\n\nI will monitor the situation and notify you when resupply becomes possible.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %2</t>
    <t id="3208">Commander,\n\nI've completed an exhaustive market analysis of %1 and surrounding sectors (within %2 jumps, minimum profit threshold: %3 Cr), but unfortunately found no profitable trading opportunities that meet our requirements.\n\nTRADE ANALYSIS REPORT:\nTotal opportunities evaluated: %4\n\nREJECTION BREAKDOWN:\n- Docking restrictions: %5 trades\n  (Station doesn't permit my ship class)\n- Insufficient profitability: %6 trades\n  (Below minimum profit threshold)\n- Insufficient volume: %7 trades\n  (Zero or negative tradeable amount)\n- Safety restrictions: %8 trades\n  (Blacklisted stations or dangerous sectors)\n\nRECOMMENDATIONS:\n- Consider adjusting profit thresholds\n- Expand maximum trading distance\n- Review sector blacklist settings\n- Wait for market conditions to improve\n\nI'll continue monitoring the market and will notify you when profitable opportunities become available.\n\nStanding by,\nAt your service</t>
    <t id="3209">Commander,\n\nURGENT ROUTE ALERT\n\nMy threat intelligence system has detected that sector %1 (threat level %2) is now in my planned trade route. For the safety of the ship and crew, I am immediately aborting the current trade operation.\n\nACTIONS TAKEN:\n- All trade orders cancelled\n- Returning to safe operations mode\n- Will find alternative trade route that avoids dangerous sectors\n- Cargo handling: Automatic (will sell any cargo at safe location if needed)\n\nThe dynamic blacklist system will prevent future trades through this sector until the threat is cleared.\n\nSafety is my first priority.\n\nWith vigilance,\nAboard %3</t>
    <t id="3210">Commander,\n\nESCAPE ROUTE INITIATED\n\nI'm currently in blacklisted sector %1 and have found a trade route that will allow me to escape safely.\n\nTRADE ROUTE:\nBuy: %2 (Sector: %3)\nSell: %4 (Sector: %5)\nWare: %6 (x%7)\nExpected Profit: %8 Cr\n\nThe ship will escape the blacklisted sector after completing this trade.\n\nRespectfully,\nAt your service</t>
    <t id="3211">Commander,\n\nISOLATED TRADING MODE\n\nI'm currently in sector %2, but all routes to other sectors are blocked by blacklisted hub sectors. This means I can only trade within my current sector until the blacklist situation changes.\n\nSITUATION:\nCurrent Sector: %2\nStatus: Isolated (non-blacklisted sector with blocked routes)\nTrading Mode: Intra-sector trades only\n\nMy trading system has automatically adjusted profit thresholds to prioritize available intra-sector trading opportunities.\n\nI will continue monitoring the situation and notify you if routes become available again.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %1</t>
    <t id="3218">Commander,\n\nROUTE PATH CHANGE DETECTED\n\nUpon entering sector %1, my navigation system detected that the route to my destination %2 (%3) has changed.\n\nPATH ANALYSIS:\n- Normal distance: %4 jumps\n- Blacklist-aware distance: %5\n- Status: %6\n\nMy navigation computer indicates that the preferred route is no longer viable due to sector travel restrictions. For the safety of the ship and crew, I am immediately aborting the current trade operation.\n\nACTIONS TAKEN:\n- All trade orders cancelled\n- Returning to safe operations mode\n- Will find alternative trade route that avoids blocked sectors\n- Cargo handling: Automatic (will sell any cargo at safe location if needed)\n\nMy navigation system will automatically avoid blocked sectors in future route planning.\n\nSafety is my first priority.\n\nWith vigilance,\nAboard %7</t>
    <t id="3219">Sector %1 cleared - All threats eliminated</t>
    <t id="3220">Commander,\n\nENEMY SHIP ESCAPED\n\nOur threat intelligence system has lost track of enemy ship %3, which has escaped from blacklisted sector %1.\n\nDETAILS:\n- Escaped Ship: %3\n- Sector Left: %1\n- Destination Sector: %2\n- Status: Tracking lost - ship has left our monitored area\n\nWhile this ship is no longer a threat in sector %1, we have lost visual contact and cannot confirm its current status or intentions in sector %2.\n\nOur tracking systems will continue monitoring sector %1 for remaining threats. If all tracked enemies leave or are eliminated, the sector will be automatically cleared from the blacklist.\n\nWith vigilance,\nThreat Intelligence System</t>
    <t id="3221">Commander,\n\nI was unable to find profitable trading opportunities at greater distances (up to %3 jumps) because these routes are currently unreachable due to sector travel restrictions (blacklisted paths).\n\nSITUATION:\nCurrent Sector: %2\nOriginal Search Range: %3 jumps\nFallback Search Range: %4 jumps\n\nI will now focus my search on nearby sectors within %4 jumps, where routes are more likely to be accessible. This should help me find profitable trades that were previously filtered out due to distance restrictions rather than actual unprofitability.\n\nI'll notify you when I find suitable trading opportunities in the nearby area.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %1</t>
    <t id="3222">Commander,\n\nSECTOR BLACKLISTED\n\nOur threat intelligence system has detected hostile activity in sector %1 and has automatically blacklisted this sector to protect our trading operations.\n\nDETECTED ENEMY SHIPS:\n%2\n\nDETECTED BY: %3\n\nFor the safety of our ships and crew, all trading routes through this sector have been blocked. Our ships will automatically route around this sector until the threat is eliminated.\n\nThe sector will be automatically cleared from the blacklist once all tracked enemy ships are eliminated or leave the area.\n\nWith vigilance,\nThreat Intelligence System</t>
    <t id="3223">Commander,\n\nI cannot find an accessible training station for my Level %1 advancement exam. I will proceed with trading operations as instructed, but I understand that I will not gain experience points until I can complete the required training. After this trade run, I will search again for any possible opportunity to train.\n\nRespectfully,\nAboard %2</t>
    <t id="3224">Training license fee: %1 Cr</t>
    <t id="3225">Bonus: I gained %1 additional skill level%2 from accumulated experience during training! Current level: %3</t>
    
    <!-- Pilot Lifecycle Messages (Roleplay Style) -->
    <t id="3214">It is an honor to work for you, %1! I am excited to begin my trading career under your command. I will do my best to serve you well and contribute to your success.</t>
    <t id="3215">Thank you for giving me this well-deserved holiday, %1! I have enjoyed my time away from trading and my skills remain intact. I am looking forward to returning to work whenever you need me. Until then, I will keep my trading knowledge sharp!</t>
    <t id="3216">I am back from holiday and ready to work again, %1! My trading skills remain sharp and I am eager to continue serving you on %2. Thank you for the well-deserved rest!</t>
    <t id="3217">Thank you for my transfer to %1, %2! I am honored by this new assignment and will take excellent care of my new ship. My trading experience and skills remain intact, and I am ready to continue serving you.</t>
    
    <!-- Fleet Messages -->
    <t id="4000">Fleet coordination: %s has been assigned route %s</t>
    <t id="4001">Fleet coordination: Route %s is fully utilized</t>
    <t id="4002">Fleet coordination: %s has released route %s</t>
    
    <!-- Territory Messages -->
    <t id="5000">%s has been assigned as primary territory for %s</t>
    <t id="5001">%s has reached expertise level %s in %s!</t>
    <t id="5002">Territory bonus applied: %s%% profit increase in %s</t>
    
    <!-- Error Messages -->
    <t id="9500">Error: %s is stuck and needs assistance!</t>
    <t id="9501">Error: Trade failed for %s</t>
    <t id="9502">Error: Cannot register %s with GalaxyTrader MK3</t>
    
    <!-- Ware Filter Messages -->
    <t id="80001">Ware %s added to blacklist</t>
    <t id="80002">Ware %s removed from blacklist</t>
    <t id="80003">Ware %s added to whitelist</t>
    <t id="80004">Automatically blacklisted (poor performance): %s</t>
    <t id="80005">Dangerous ware prioritized: %s</t>
    <t id="80006">Ware filter: %s active, %s trading blocked</t>
    <t id="80007">All ware filters cleared</t>
    <t id="80008">Ware filters reset to default</t>
    <t id="80009">Ware Filter Management</t>
    <t id="80010">Blocked Wares</t>
    <t id="80011">Allowed Wares</t>
    <t id="80012">Dangerous Ware Handling</t>
    <t id="80013">Minimum Ware Value</t>
    <t id="80014">Maximum Ware Value</t>
    <t id="80015">Restricted Factions</t>
    <t id="80016">Ware categories updated from current game state</t>
    <t id="80017">%s wares categorized: %s low-value, %s dangerous, %s high-value</t>
    <t id="80018">Dynamic ware categorization enabled</t>
    <t id="80019">Auto-blacklisting for category %s disabled</t>
    <t id="80020">New wares from other mods detected and categorized</t>
    
    <!-- Global Settings UI -->
    <t id="9000">GalaxyTrader - Global Settings</t>
    <t id="9010">XP and Training System</t>
    <t id="9012">Automatic Training</t>
    <t id="9013">XP Multiplier</t>
    <t id="9015">Commander Bonus Percent</t>
    <t id="9020">Fleet Coordination</t>
    <t id="9021">Enable Fleet Coordination</t>
    <t id="9023">Enable Trade Cache</t>
    <t id="9030">Notifications</t>
    <t id="9031">Notification Level</t>
    <t id="9040">Auto-Repair System</t>
    <t id="9041">Enable Auto-Repair</t>
    <t id="9042">Hull Repair Threshold</t>
    <t id="9043">Minimum Pilot Level</t>
    
    <!-- Trading Price Ranges Settings -->
    <t id="9004">Trading Price Ranges</t>
    <t id="9005">Sell Offer Price Max</t>
    <t id="9006">Buy Offer Price Min</t>
    <t id="9007">Isolated: Sell Price Max</t>
    <t id="9008">Isolated: Buy Price Min</t>
    <t id="9009">Fallback: Sell Price Max</t>
    <t id="9014">Fallback: Buy Price Min</t>
    <t id="9016">Profit Threshold Base</t>
    <t id="9025">Min Player Money</t>
    <t id="9024">Cache Dropoff Tolerance</t>
    <t id="9054">Block Enemy Faction Sectors</t>
    <t id="9055">Blacklist Threat Level</t>
    <t id="9056">Recreate Blacklist</t>
    <t id="9057">Recreate</t>
    <t id="9058">Assign to GT ships</t>
    <t id="9059">Assign</t>
    
    <!-- Global Settings Tooltips -->
    <t id="9112">Automatically sends pilots for training when they reach required levels. Disable to manually control training timing.</t>
    <t id="9113">Adjusts how fast pilots gain experience. Higher values mean faster progression.</t>
    <t id="9115">Percentage of subordinate XP awarded to commander pilots. Set to 0% to disable commander bonus XP. Default: 10%.</t>
    <t id="9121">Enables intelligent fleet coordination features including route optimization and load balancing.</t>
    <t id="9123">Allows sharing profitable trade opportunities between fleet members for better coordination.</t>
    <t id="9131">Controls how many notifications are shown: 0=Quiet, 1=Important only, 2=All notifications</t>
    <t id="9141">Automatically sends ships for repairs after completing trades when hull falls below threshold. Only for experienced pilots (Level 12+). Ships choose appropriate facility: S/M Equipment Dock, L/XL Shipyard.</t>
    <t id="9142">Hull percentage below which auto-repair is triggered. Default: 95%. Ships will automatically go to nearest repair facility when damaged.</t>
    <t id="9143">Minimum pilot level required for auto-repair feature. Default: 12 (experienced traders). Lower level pilots must repair manually.</t>
    <t id="9104">Maximum relative price for sell offers (ship buys FROM stations). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: 0.5 (50% above average). Higher = more expensive but more options.</t>
    <t id="9105">Minimum relative price for buy offers (ship sells TO stations). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: -0.5 (50% below average). Lower = cheaper buyers but more options.</t>
    <t id="9106">Sell price max for isolated ships (stuck in single sector). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: 0.5.</t>
    <t id="9107">Buy price min for isolated ships (stuck in single sector). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: -0.5.</t>
    <t id="9108">Sell price max for fallback search (last resort when normal search fails). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: 0.5. Fallback search uses MaxDistance=2 and relaxed profit thresholds.</t>
    <t id="9109">Buy price min for fallback search (last resort when normal search fails). Range: -1.0 to +1.0. Default: -0.5. Fallback search uses MaxDistance=2 and relaxed profit thresholds.</t>
    <t id="9116">Base minimum profit at Level 15 for a medium trader (reference cargo 8200). Actual MinAbsoluteProfit is computed per pilot + scaled by cargo:\n\nbase(L) = Base * ((L-1)^2 / 14^2)\nscaled = base(L) * (cargo / 8200)\nfinal = max(scaled, 25% of base(L))\n\nSet to 0 to accept any profit (only ROI/distance/other filters apply).</t>
    <t id="9125">Minimum player money (credits) required before ships will search for trades. When player money falls below this threshold, all ships skip trade searches and wait, preventing expensive cache scanning that causes game stutter. Range: 1,000 - 100,000 Cr. Default: 1,000 Cr.</t>
    <t id="9124">Maximum percentage ROI drop from cached value before rejecting trade. Example: 20% cached ROI with 15% tolerance accepts down to 17% ROI (14% drop).</t>
    <t id="9154">Automatically blacklist all sectors owned by enemy factions (relation checkbox in blacklist)</t>
    <t id="9155">Minimum threat level (1-5) required to blacklist a sector:\n2=Medium (single attack)\n3=Medium-High (hostile factions)\n4=High (capital ships/missiles)\n5=Very High (Xenon/Khaak)</t>
    <t id="9156">Manually recreate the threat avoidance blacklist (useful if it was deleted)</t>
    <t id="9157">Manually assign the current dynamic blacklist to all GT fleet commander ships. Subordinates inherit from their commander.</t>
    
    <!-- Trader Titles (English) -->
    <t id="6001">Apprentice</t>
    <t id="6002">Courier</t>
    <t id="6003">Supplier</t>
    <t id="6004">Trader</t>
    <t id="6005">Merchant</t>
    <t id="6006">Long-Distance Merchant</t>
    
    <!-- Defensive Equipment Balance Profiles -->
    <t id="6101">Balanced</t>
    <t id="6102">Defensive</t>
    <t id="6103">Trading-Focused</t>
    <t id="6104">Heavy Defense</t>
    <t id="6105">Tower Support</t>
    
    <!-- Threat Avoidance System Settings -->
    <t id="9050">Threat Avoidance System</t>
    <t id="9051">Enable Threat Avoidance:</t>
    <t id="9052">Hostile Relation Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9053">Use Dynamic Blacklist:</t>
    <t id="9151">Level 6+ traders detect hostile ships and avoid dangerous routes. Disabling stops all scanning (improves performance). Risk tolerance per ship in command behavior (0-10 scale).</t>
    <t id="9152">Only flag factions with relation at or below this value as threats. Default: -20%</t>
    <t id="9153">Automatically blacklist dangerous sectors (threat level 3+) to force ships to route around threats. Uses vanilla pathfinding for alternative routes.</t>
    
    <!-- Defensive Equipment Settings -->
    <t id="9060">Defensive Equipment Auto-Replenishment (Level 15)</t>
    <t id="9061">Enable Auto-Replenishment:</t>
    <t id="9062">Restock Countermeasures:</t>
    <t id="9063">Restock Defense Drones:</t>
    <t id="9064">Restock Trade Drones:</t>
    <t id="9065">Restock Laser Towers:</t>
    <t id="9066">Restock Repair Drones:</t>
    <t id="9067">Countermeasure Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9068">Unified Capacity Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9069">Equipment Balance Profile:</t>
    <t id="9161">Master Traders (Level 15) automatically restock defensive equipment after trades. Applies to commander level for subordinates.</t>
    <t id="9162">All ships (S/M/L/XL). Separate capacity. Critical for missile defense.</t>
    <t id="9163">L/XL ships only. Shares unified capacity with other deployables.</t>
    <t id="9164">L/XL ships only. Essential for trading operations. Shares unified capacity.</t>
    <t id="9165">All ships. L/XL ships share unified capacity, S/M use cargo.</t>
    <t id="9166">L/XL ships only. Works with auto-repair system. Shares unified capacity.</t>
    <t id="9167">Restock when countermeasures below this percentage (all ships, separate capacity).</t>
    <t id="9168">Restock when total deployables below this percentage (L/XL ships: drones + towers share one capacity).</t>
    <t id="9169">Distribution of unified capacity (L/XL ships): Trading-Focused (20/50/20/10), Balanced (35/35/20/10), Defensive (50/20/20/10), Heavy Defense (40/30/20/10), Tower Support (30/30/30/10). Ratios: Defense/Trade/Towers/Repair. Click to cycle through options.</t>
    
    <!-- Ship Modifications Settings -->
    <t id="9090">Ship Modifications</t>
    <t id="9091">Enable Ship Modifications</t>
    <t id="9191">Automatically install ship and engine modifications based on pilot level. Level 9+ = Level 1 mods, Level 12+ = Level 2 mods, Level 15+ = Level 3 mods. Only GT-installed mods are removed when order is cancelled.</t>
    
    <!-- Ship Naming Settings -->
    <t id="9070">Ship Naming Configuration</t>
    <t id="9071">Display XP:</t>
    <t id="9072">Display Rank:</t>
    <t id="9073">Display Level:</t>
    <t id="9074">Display Status:</t>
    <t id="9075">Enable Ship Renaming:</t>
    <t id="9076">Prefix</t>
    <t id="9077">Suffix</t>
    <t id="9078">Default Name Source:</t>
    <t id="9079">Model Name</t>
    <t id="9080">Type Name</t>
    <t id="9081">Model Base</t>
    <t id="9083">Custom Name</t>
    <t id="9082">Display Ship Class:</t>
    <t id="9171">Show XP values in ship names</t>
    <t id="9175">Enable or disable automatic ship renaming with pilot information</t>
    <t id="9172">Show rank titles in ship names</t>
    <t id="9173">Show level numbers in ship names</t>
    <t id="9174">Show trading status in ship names</t>
    <t id="9178">Choose the source for ship base names: Model Name (with variant), Type Name (generic), Model Base (without variant), or Custom Name (stored name)</t>
    <t id="9182">Show ship class (S, M, L, XL) in ship names</t>
    
    <!-- Debug Settings -->
    <t id="9200">Debug Settings</t>
    <t id="9201">Enable Debug Logging:</t>
    <t id="9202">Master toggle for all debug_text output. When disabled, all debug logging is suppressed. When enabled, debug messages appear in the DebugLog based on individual debug_text chance values.</t>
    
    <!-- Maintenance and Diagnostics Settings -->
    <t id="9220">Maintenance &amp; Diagnostics</t>
    <t id="9221">Reset Profit Statistics:</t>
    <t id="9222">RESET</t>
    <t id="9223">Clear All Blacklisted Sectors:</t>
    <t id="9224">CLEAR</t>
    <t id="9225">Reset All Settings to Defaults:</t>
    <t id="9226">RESET ALL</t>
    <t id="9323">Removes all sectors from the threat intelligence blacklist. This will immediately clear all blacklisted sectors and allow your ships to travel to previously blocked areas. Use this if you want to reset the threat avoidance system or if sectors were incorrectly blacklisted.</t>
    <t id="9321">Resets all profit statistics to 0 for all pilots and ships. Use this after upgrading to v0.6.0 to clear inflated revenue-based statistics. The fix now tracks actual PROFIT (revenue - purchase cost). Trade counts and XP are preserved.</t>
    <t id="9325">Resets all global settings to their default values. This includes XP settings, Fleet Coordination, Notifications, Mobile Intel, Threat Avoidance, Ship Naming, Auto-Repair, Modifications, Performance, and Number Format settings. Debug logging setting is preserved to allow logging of the reset operation.</t>
    <t id="9227">Clear Trade Cache for All Home Sectors:</t>
    <t id="9228">CLEAR CACHE</t>
    <t id="9327">Clears the trade cache for all home sectors. This will force all ships to perform fresh live searches on their next trade search. Use this if the cache appears stale or corrupted, or if you want to force a complete cache refresh.</t>
    <t id="9229">Release all search locks</t>
    <t id="9329">Releases ALL in-flight trade-search locks and clears related transient state. Use this if ships are stuck on “Searching for trades” due to stale locks from old saves. This may interrupt legitimate searches.</t>
    <t id="9290">Dump Trade Hub Status:</t>
    <t id="9291">DUMP</t>
    <t id="9390">Shows a one-shot snapshot of the centralized trade hub (scheduler queues + last requesting ship status) in the log and as a notification.</t>
    <t id="9292">Dump Trade Cache (FULL):</t>
    <t id="9293">DUMP CACHE</t>
    <t id="9392">FULL cache dump (can be huge). Writes all cache entries to DebugLog in chunks. Click again to cancel.</t>
    <t id="9294">Clear Fleet Reservations:</t>
    <t id="9295">{77000,9224}</t>
    <t id="9394">Clears all active fleet trade reservations. Use this if ships appear stuck waiting for reserved trades to expire, or if the reservation table has become stale after loading an old save.</t>
    
    <!-- Performance Settings -->
    <t id="9230">Performance</t>
    <t id="9231">Batch Processing Delay:</t>
    <t id="9232">Validation Delay:</t>
    <t id="9233">Max Concurrent Searches:</t>
    <t id="9234">Max Trades To Return:</t>
    <t id="9235">Max Offers Per Ware:</t>
    <t id="9236">Max Trades Per Ware:</t>
    <t id="9237">Max Offers Per Ware For Matching:</t>
    <t id="9238">Early Exit Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9241">Live Offer Slice Interval:</t>
    <t id="9266">Search Lock TTL:</t>
    <t id="9263">Batch Chunk Size:</t>
    <t id="9239">Number Format</t>
    <t id="9240">Format Style:</t>
    <t id="9242">Use M Suffix</t>
    <t id="9243">M Suffix Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9244">German (123.456,78)</t>
    <t id="9245">English (123,456.78)</t>
    <t id="9510">Level-Up Popup Notifications:</t>
    <t id="9511">Training Required Alerts:</t>
    <t id="9512">Training Completed Notifications:</t>
    <t id="9513">Profit Reports:</t>
    <t id="9514">Market Alerts:</t>
    <t id="9515">Fleet Updates:</t>
    <t id="9516">Use vanilla XP only</t>
    <t id="9610">Enable or disable trader level-up popup notifications in the player UI.</t>
    <t id="9611">Alert when pilots need training to advance to the next level.</t>
    <t id="9612">Notify when pilots complete training and advance in rank.</t>
    <t id="9613">Periodic profit summaries (simple and comprehensive reports).</t>
    <t id="9614">Exceptional market opportunities and high-value trade alerts.</t>
    <t id="9615">Fleet coordination messages and status updates.</t>
    <t id="9616">Use pilot.skill.piloting and disable GT XP progression/caps.</t>
    <t id="9246">Simple Report Frequency:</t>
    <t id="9247">Comprehensive Report Frequency:</t>
    <t id="9248">Max Concurrent Cache Searches:</t>
    <t id="9249">Max Concurrent Live Searches:</t>
    <t id="9340">Choose number format: German uses '.' for thousands and ',' for decimals (123.456,78), English uses ',' for thousands and '.' for decimals (123,456.78)</t>
    <t id="9342">Enable M suffix for numbers greater than threshold (e.g., 1.0 M instead of 1,000,000)</t>
    <t id="9343">Threshold for M suffix. Numbers above this value will be displayed with M suffix (default: 999,999)</t>
    <t id="9346">Frequency of simple report (popup notification): 1-30 minutes (default: 1 minute). Use Profit Reports toggle to disable.</t>
    <t id="9347">Frequency of comprehensive report (logbook entry): 1-60 minutes (default: 30 minutes). Use Profit Reports toggle to disable.</t>
    <t id="9398">Use GT Credits Due Override</t>
    <t id="9399">Replace or augment the vanilla "CR due from trades" line with the GT projected value in the same UI slot.</t>
    <t id="9331">Delay between batches during trade search processing (1-500ms). Higher values reduce CPU load but slow down trade searches. Default: 120ms. Used in batch processor and trade list filtering.</t>
    <t id="9332">Delay between trade validations in AI script (1-500ms). Higher values reduce CPU load but slow down trade validation. Default: 50ms. Used when validating trade list from MD system.</t>
    <t id="9333">Maximum number of trade searches that can run simultaneously (1-10). Lower values reduce CPU load but increase queue wait times. Higher values process searches faster but may cause performance spikes. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9334">Maximum number of trades to return from cache search (1-100). Higher values provide more trade options but increase cache validation time. Lower values reduce CPU load but may miss viable trades. Default: 20.</t>
    <t id="9335">Maximum number of offers per ware to process in live search (5-100). Higher values consider more offers but increase processing time. Lower values reduce CPU load but may miss profitable trades. Default: 20.</t>
    <t id="9336">Maximum number of trades per ware during batch processing (5-100). Higher values allow more trades per ware but increase processing time. Lower values reduce CPU load but may miss profitable trades. Default: 20.</t>
    <t id="9337">Maximum number of offers per ware for matching in batch processor (5-100). Higher values consider more offers but increase processing time. Lower values reduce CPU load but may miss profitable trades. Default: 20.</t>
    <t id="9338">Early exit threshold for batch processing (100-10000). When this many trades are found, batch processing stops early to save CPU. Higher values process more trades but increase CPU load. Lower values exit sooner but may miss profitable trades. Default: 2000.</t>
    <t id="9341">Live offer slice interval in milliseconds (5-2000ms). Controls how often live offer slices can start. Lower values allow faster offer collection but increase CPU load. Higher values reduce CPU load but slow down live search processing. Default: 500ms.</t>
    <t id="9363">Batch processing chunk size (5-20). Processes chunkSize×chunkSize combinations per chunk (e.g., 5×5 = 25 combinations). Larger chunks improve throughput but increase CPU load per chunk. Smaller chunks reduce CPU spikes but require more continuations. Default: 5.</t>
    <t id="9348">Maximum number of cache searches that can run simultaneously (1-20). Cache searches are fast and cheap; lower values can reduce burstiness under huge fleets. Default: 2.</t>
    <t id="9349">Maximum number of live searches that can run simultaneously (1-10). Live searches are CPU-intensive, so lower values reduce CPU load but increase queue wait times. Higher values process searches faster but may cause performance spikes. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9264">Cache Query Chunk Size:</t>
    <t id="9265">Live Offer Append Chunk Size:</t>
    <t id="9364">Cache entries validated per chunk (10-200). Smaller values spread cache validation across more frames (smoother) but may increase time to find a cached trade. Default: 10.</t>
    <t id="9365">Offers appended per append-slice (50-2000). Smaller values reduce per-frame list-append work (smoother) but may slow live search completion. Default: 200.</t>
    <t id="9366">Search lock time-to-live in seconds (60-7200). If a ship is denied with "trade search already in progress" for longer than this, GT will self-heal by clearing stale search state and releasing the lock. Default: 600s.</t>
    <t id="9370">Batch Backpressure Soft Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9371">Batch Backpressure Hard Threshold:</t>
    <t id="9372">Sectors Per Slice:</t>
    <t id="9373">Home Refresh Cooldown:</t>
    <t id="9374">Cache Miss Cooldown Base:</t>
    <t id="9375">Scheduler Tick Interval:</t>
    <t id="9376">Max Cache Queries Per Tick:</t>
    <t id="9377">Max Search Continuations Per Tick:</t>
    <t id="9378">Max Ships Per Tick:</t>
    <t id="9379">Max Items Per Tick:</t>
    <t id="9380">Max Wake Per Tick:</t>
    <t id="9381">Cache Query Max Entries:</t>
    <t id="9382">Stale Threshold Seconds:</t>
    <t id="9383">Queue Stale Threshold Seconds:</t>
    <t id="9384">Failed Trade Expiration Seconds:</t>
    <t id="9385">Max Concurrent Fallback Searches:</t>
    <t id="9386">{77000,9385}</t>
    <t id="9470">Soft threshold for batch processor backlog (5-50). When backlog reaches this value, backpressure starts being applied to slow down new search requests. Lower values trigger backpressure sooner (more conservative). Default: 10.</t>
    <t id="9471">Hard threshold for batch processor backlog (10-100). When backlog reaches this value, new live searches are blocked until backlog decreases. Lower values block searches sooner (more conservative). Default: 25.</t>
    <t id="9472">Sectors processed per slice in live offer collection (1-5). Smaller values spread work across more frames (smoother) but may slow down offer collection. Larger values process faster but may cause frame spikes. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9473">Cooldown after home-sector refresh completes (10-120 seconds). Prevents excessive refresh requests. Lower values allow more frequent refreshes but increase CPU load. Higher values reduce refresh frequency but may delay cache updates. Default: 30s.</t>
    <t id="9474">Base cooldown after cache miss before retrying live search (1-30 seconds). Prevents excessive retry attempts. Lower values retry sooner but increase CPU load. Higher values reduce retry frequency but may delay trade finding. Default: 10s.</t>
    <t id="9475">Interval between scheduler ticks in milliseconds (50-500ms). Controls how often the scheduler processes work queue. Lower values process more frequently but increase CPU load. Higher values reduce CPU load but may increase queue wait times. Default: 100ms.</t>
    <t id="9476">Maximum cache queries started per scheduler tick (1-5). Limits cache query rate to prevent frame blocking. Lower values reduce CPU spikes but slow down cache searches. Higher values process faster but may cause stutter. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9477">Maximum search continuations started per scheduler tick (1-5). Limits continuation rate to prevent frame blocking. Lower values reduce CPU spikes but slow down search processing. Higher values process faster but may cause stutter. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9478">Maximum ships processed per scheduler tick (1-5). Limits ship processing rate to prevent frame blocking. Lower values reduce CPU spikes but slow down queue processing. Higher values process faster but may cause stutter. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9479">Maximum work items processed per scheduler tick (1-5). Limits work item processing rate to prevent frame blocking. Lower values reduce CPU spikes but slow down queue processing. Higher values process faster but may cause stutter. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9480">Maximum waiters woken per scheduler tick (1-10). Limits wake rate to prevent CPU spikes when many waiters are queued. Lower values reduce CPU spikes but slow down waiter processing. Higher values process faster but may cause stutter. Default: 2.</t>
    <t id="9481">Maximum cache entries queried per batch (1-100). Controls cache query batch size. Lower values make cache searches faster but may miss better trades. Higher values consider more cached trades but increase validation time. Default: 5.</t>
    <t id="9482">Live search state stale threshold in seconds (60-600). When live search state is older than this, it's considered stale and cleared. Lower values clear stale state sooner but may interrupt legitimate searches. Higher values allow longer searches but may leave stale state. Default: 300s.</t>
    <t id="9483">Queue item stale threshold in seconds (30-300). When queue items are older than this, they're considered stale and removed. Lower values clear stale items sooner but may remove legitimate queued items. Higher values allow longer queue times but may leave stale items. Default: 60s.</t>
    <t id="9484">Failed trade cache expiration in seconds (300-3600). Failed trades are cached to avoid retrying immediately. Lower values expire failed trades sooner (more retries) but reduce cache effectiveness. Higher values cache longer (fewer retries) but may delay retry attempts. Default: 1800s (30 minutes).</t>
    <t id="9485">Maximum concurrent fallback live searches (1-10). Fallback searches bypass home-sector lock, allowing multiple ships from the same home sector to search simultaneously. Lower values reduce CPU load but may slow down fallback searches. Higher values allow more parallel fallback searches but increase CPU usage. Default: 1.</t>
    <t id="9490">Trade Found Signal Delay:</t>
    <t id="9590">Delay before sending GT_Trade_Found signal to ships in milliseconds (10-1000ms). Ships always wait (configured delay + 5ms buffer) before sending new requests to catch delayed signals. Higher values spread signals across frames for smoother performance. Default: 10ms.</t>
    
    <!-- GalaxyTrader Info Menu UI -->
    <t id="8000">GalaxyTrader Fleet</t>
    <t id="8001">GalaxyTrader fleet management and pilot statistics</t>
    <t id="8002">View and manage all GalaxyTrader pilots</t>
    
    <!-- Column Headers -->
    <t id="8100">Ship ID</t>
    <t id="8101">Pilot</t>
    <t id="8102">Ship</t>
    <t id="8103">Status</t>
    <t id="8104">Rank</t>
    <t id="8105">Level</t>
    <t id="8106">XP</t>
    <t id="8107">Lifetime Profit</t>
    <t id="8108">Location</t>
    <t id="8109">Home Base</t>
    <t id="8110">Last Trade</t>
    <t id="8111">Pilot Profit</t>
    <t id="8112">Ship Profit</t>
    <t id="8113">Trade Count</t>
    
    <!-- Actions -->
    <t id="8200">Refresh</t>
    <t id="8201">Export CSV</t>
    <t id="8202">Statistics</t>
    <t id="8203">Settings</t>
    <t id="8204">Help</t>
    <t id="8205">Close</t>
    
    <!-- Filter Options -->
    <t id="8300">All Pilots</t>
    <t id="8301">Trading</t>
    <t id="8302">Training</t>
    <t id="8303">Maintenance</t>
    <t id="8304">Emergency</t>
    <t id="8305">Beginners (Lv 1-5)</t>
    <t id="8306">Advanced (Lv 6-11)</t>
    <t id="8307">Experts (Lv 12+)</t>
    <t id="8308">Top 10 Earners</t>
    
    <!-- Sort Options -->
    <t id="8350">Sort by:</t>
    <t id="8351">Ship ID</t>
    <t id="8352">Pilot Name</t>
    <t id="8353">Ship Type</t>
    <t id="8354">Status</t>
    <t id="8355">Rank</t>
    <t id="8356">Level</t>
    <t id="8357">XP</t>
    <t id="8358">Profit</t>
    
    <!-- Messages -->
    <t id="8400">No pilots registered</t>
    <t id="8401">No pilots match filter</t>
    <t id="8402">Total Pilots:</t>
    <t id="8403">Total Fleet Profit:</t>
    <t id="8404">Last updated:</t>
    <t id="8405">Search pilots...</t>
    
    <!-- Column Headers -->
    <t id="8114">Sector</t>
    
    <!-- Renaming Tab -->
    <t id="8320">Ship Renaming</t>
    <t id="8321">Custom Name</t>
    <t id="8322">Set Name</t>
    <t id="8323">Clear Name</t>
    <t id="8324">Name set successfully</t>
    <t id="8325">Name cleared successfully</t>
    
    <!-- Action Buttons -->
    <t id="8450">Send to Training</t>
    <t id="8451">Deregister</t>
    <t id="8452">Force Sell Cargo</t>
    <t id="8453">Send to Repair</t>
    <t id="8454">Send to Resupply</t>
    <t id="8455">Stop All Orders</t>
    <t id="8456">Actions</t>
    
    <!-- Tooltips -->
    <t id="8500">Click to sort by Ship ID</t>
    <t id="8501">Click to sort by Pilot Name</t>
    <t id="8502">Click to sort by Ship Type</t>
    <t id="8503">Click to sort by Status</t>
    <t id="8504">Click to sort by Rank</t>
    <t id="8505">Click to sort by Level</t>
    <t id="8506">Click to sort by XP</t>
    <t id="8507">Click to sort by Lifetime Profit</t>
    <t id="8508">Refresh pilot data from mission system</t>
    <t id="8509">Export current view to CSV file</t>
    <t id="8510">View fleet statistics and charts</t>
    <t id="8511">Configure menu settings</t>
    <t id="8512">Show help and keyboard shortcuts</t>
    <t id="8600">No GalaxyTrader pilots found</t>
    <t id="8601">Create pilots by assigning ships to GalaxyTrader, or wait for data to load.</t>
    
    <!-- Context Menu Rename -->
    <t id="9001">GT Rename</t>
    <t id="9902">{77000,8450}</t>
    <t id="9903">Manual training queued for %1. Pilot will begin training after current cycle.</t>
    <t id="9904">Training queued after current cycle</t>
    <t id="9905">Pilot or ship not found</t>
    <t id="9906">AutoTraining is enabled - manual queue not required</t>
    <t id="9907">Pilot is not training blocked</t>
    
    <!-- APPRENTICE LEVEL PENALTIES (Levels 1-2) - Ship class dependent -->
    <!-- Small ships: NO PENALTY (no modifications needed) -->
    
    <!-- Medium ships: -5% penalty -->
    <t id="11011">GT Apprentice Medium Ship Reducer</t>
    <t id="11012">Engine modification that slightly reduces performance for inexperienced pilots on medium ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -5% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="11013">GT Apprentice Medium Travel Reducer</t>
    <t id="11014">Engine modification that slightly reduces travel performance for inexperienced pilots on medium ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -5% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- Large ships: -15% penalty -->
    <t id="11021">GT Apprentice Large Ship Reducer</t>
    <t id="11022">Engine modification that reduces performance for inexperienced pilots on large ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -15% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="11023">GT Apprentice Large Travel Reducer</t>
    <t id="11024">Engine modification that reduces travel performance for inexperienced pilots on large ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -15% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- Capital ships: -25% penalty -->
    <t id="11031">GT Apprentice Capital Ship Reducer</t>
    <t id="11032">Engine modification that significantly reduces performance for inexperienced pilots on capital ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -25% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="11033">GT Apprentice Capital Travel Reducer</t>
    <t id="11034">Engine modification that significantly reduces travel performance for inexperienced pilots on capital ships. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -25% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- BASIC CERTIFIED LEVEL - Small ships (Levels 3-8) -->
    <t id="12001">GT Basic Small Ship Enhancer</t>
    <t id="12002">Specialized engine modification for small ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +3% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="12003">GT Basic Small Travel Enhancer</t>
    <t id="12004">Specialized engine modification for small ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +3% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- BASIC CERTIFIED LEVEL - Large ships (Levels 3-8) -->
    <t id="13001">GT Basic Large Ship Reducer</t>
    <t id="13002">Specialized engine modification for large ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -8% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="13003">GT Basic Large Travel Reducer</t>
    <t id="13004">Specialized engine modification for large ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -8% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- BASIC CERTIFIED LEVEL - Capital ships (Levels 3-8) -->
    <t id="14001">GT Basic Capital Ship Reducer</t>
    <t id="14002">Specialized engine modification for capital ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -15% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="14003">GT Basic Capital Travel Reducer</t>
    <t id="14004">Specialized engine modification for capital ships with basic certified pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. -15% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- EXPERT LEVEL BONUSES - Small/Medium ships (Level 9+) -->
    <t id="15001">GT Expert Small Ship Enhancer</t>
    <t id="15002">Advanced engine modification for small ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +25% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="15003">GT Expert Small Travel Enhancer</t>
    <t id="15004">Advanced engine modification for small ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +25% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- EXPERT LEVEL BONUSES - Large ships (Level 9+) -->
    <t id="16001">GT Expert Large Ship Enhancer</t>
    <t id="16002">Advanced engine modification for large ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +15% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="16003">GT Expert Large Travel Enhancer</t>
    <t id="16004">Advanced engine modification for large ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +15% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- EXPERT LEVEL BONUSES - Capital ships (Level 9+) -->
    <t id="17001">GT Expert Capital Ship Enhancer</t>
    <t id="17002">Advanced engine modification for capital ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +6% speed, thrust and rotation.</t>
    <t id="17003">GT Expert Capital Travel Enhancer</t>
    <t id="17004">Advanced engine modification for capital ships with expert pilots. Used by GalaxyTrader AI system. +6% travel speed.</t>
    
    <!-- PENALTY MODIFICATIONS - Skill Limitation Penalties -->
    <!-- These represent performance penalties for inexperienced pilots on larger ships -->
    <!-- Separate translations for ship and engine mods (X4 doesn't allow same ware for both types) -->
    
    <!-- Ship Penalty Mods -->
    <t id="18001">Severe Skill Limitation (Ship)</t>
    <t id="18002">Severe Skill Limitation (Ship) - Represents severe performance penalties due to pilot inexperience with large vessels. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Increases ship mass. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    <t id="18003">Moderate Skill Limitation (Ship)</t>
    <t id="18004">Moderate Skill Limitation (Ship) - Represents moderate performance penalties as pilot adapts to vessel complexity. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Increases ship mass. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    <t id="18005">Light Skill Limitation (Ship)</t>
    <t id="18006">Light Skill Limitation (Ship) - Represents minor performance penalties during pilot skill development. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Increases ship mass. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    
    <!-- Engine Penalty Mods -->
    <t id="18007">Severe Skill Limitation (Engine)</t>
    <t id="18008">Severe Skill Limitation (Engine) - Represents severe performance penalties due to pilot inexperience with large vessels. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Reduces engine thrust and rotation. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    <t id="18009">Moderate Skill Limitation (Engine)</t>
    <t id="18010">Moderate Skill Limitation (Engine) - Represents moderate performance penalties as pilot adapts to vessel complexity. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Reduces engine thrust and rotation. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    <t id="18011">Light Skill Limitation (Engine)</t>
    <t id="18012">Light Skill Limitation (Engine) - Represents minor performance penalties during pilot skill development. Automatically applied by GalaxyTrader system when pilot skill is insufficient for ship size. Reduces engine thrust and rotation. (GT System Only - Not Available for Manual Installation)</t>
    
    <!-- Ship State Naming -->
    <t id="9250">Ship State Naming</t>
    <t id="9350">Customize ship state abbreviations. Default values are shown in input boxes and can be overridden. Maximum 3 characters. All ship names will automatically update when changed.</t>
    <t id="9251">Resupply State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9252">Repair State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9253">Maintenance State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9254">Training State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9255">Reroute State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9256">Clearance State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9257">Blocked State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9258">Fallback State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9259">Isolated State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9260">Trading State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9261">Idle State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9262">Escape State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9268">Unreachable State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9269">Pilot Exchange State Abbreviation:</t>
    <t id="9270">Custom Blacklist Prefix Tag:</t>
    <t id="9351">Abbreviation for Resupply state (default: RS)</t>
    <t id="9352">Abbreviation for Repair state (default: RP)</t>
    <t id="9353">Abbreviation for Maintenance state (default: MT)</t>
    <t id="9354">Abbreviation for Training state (default: TR)</t>
    <t id="9355">Abbreviation for Reroute state (default: RR)</t>
    <t id="9356">Abbreviation for Clearance state (default: CL)</t>
    <t id="9357">Abbreviation for Blocked state (default: BL)</t>
    <t id="9358">Abbreviation for Fallback state (default: FB)</t>
    <t id="9359">Abbreviation for Isolated state (default: IS)</t>
    <t id="9360">Abbreviation for Trading state (default: TD)</t>
    <t id="9361">Abbreviation for Idle state (default: ID)</t>
    <t id="9362">Abbreviation for Escape state (default: ES)</t>
    <t id="9367">Abbreviation for Unreachable state (default: UR)</t>
    <t id="9368">Abbreviation for Pilot Exchange state (default: PE)</t>
    <t id="9369">Shown as prefix for MK3 ships affected by a custom faction blacklist (including subordinates). Default: CB</t>
    
    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <!-- GalaxyTrader MK1 — Station Trader          -->
    <!-- ID Range: 30000–30999                      -->
    <!-- ========================================== -->
    
    <!-- Order Name and Description -->
    <t id="30002">GalaxyTrader MK1</t>
    <t id="30102">Station trader — sells station products to NPC factions</t>
    
    <!-- Parameter Labels -->
    <t id="30010">Home Station</t>
    <t id="30011">Max Sell Distance</t>
    <t id="30012">Ignore Trade Rules</t>
    <t id="30013">Ware Filter</t>
    <t id="30014">Sell Cargo Fill Target %</t>
    <t id="30015">Backtrack Tolerance</t>
    <t id="30016">Buy Cargo Fill Target %</t>
    <t id="30017">Logbook Entries</t>
    <t id="30018">Notification Level</t>
    <t id="30019">Fleet Coordination</t>
    <t id="30020">Debug Level</t>
    <t id="30021">Supply Station</t>
    <t id="30022">Min Station Storage %</t>
    <t id="30023">Allow Illegal Wares</t>
    <t id="30024">Cargo/Profit</t>
    <t id="30025">Allow Multi-Trade</t>
    <t id="30026">Return Home Between Cycles</t>
    
    <!-- Parameter Tooltips -->
    <t id="30110">Player station to sell wares from (station assignment required)</t>
    <t id="30111">Maximum gate distance for finding NPC buyers (limited by pilot skill)</t>
    <t id="30112">Ignore station trade restrictions — sell to any friendly faction regardless of station trade rules</t>
    <t id="30113">Optional ware filter; leave empty to sell all station products and tradewares</t>
    <t id="30114">Minimum cargo fill percentage before departing on sell trips</t>
    <t id="30115">Max extra jumps allowed when adding a second ware to a trip (0 = only buyers directly on the route)</t>
    <t id="30116">Target cargo fill for supply runs (soft target, trader may depart earlier)</t>
    <t id="30117">Enable per-trade logbook entries</t>
    <t id="30118">Notification level: 0=Quiet, 1=Normal, 2=Verbose</t>
    <t id="30119">Enable fleet coordination and trade reservation system</t>
    <t id="30120">Debug logging level: 0=Off, 1=Normal, 2=Verbose</t>
    <t id="30121">When enabled, also buy resources for the station. Supply takes priority when storage drops below minimum threshold</t>
    <t id="30122">When any resource drops below this percentage of its target, supply takes priority over selling. Ignored if station cannot afford resources</t>
    <t id="30123">Allow selling or buying illegal/contraband wares when available</t>
    <t id="30124">Sell selection: 1 = Cargo (prefer highest station storage fill % for that ware; ties broken by profit score), 2 = Profit (highest profit score)</t>
    <t id="30125">Allow chaining multiple sell trades in one cycle (up to 3 wares/targets). Disable to run single-trade cycles only</t>
    <t id="30126">When enabled, return to home station and dock between trade cycles. When disabled, continue searching from current location (legacy behavior)</t>
    
    <!-- Logbook and Notification Messages -->
    <t id="30200">Selling %1 %2 from %3 to %4</t>
    <t id="30201">No buyers found for station products within %1 jumps</t>
    <t id="30202">Home station %1 destroyed — station trader order cancelled</t>
    <t id="30203">Home station %1 is no longer player-owned — order cancelled</t>
    <t id="30204">Station assignment required — order cancelled</t>
    <t id="30205">MK1 Station Trader started at %1</t>
    <t id="30206">Completed sale: %1 %2 sold to %3 for %4 Cr (profit: %5 Cr)</t>
    <t id="30207">Multi-ware trip: delivering %1 wares to %2 destinations</t>
    <t id="30208">Supplying %1 %2 to %3 from %4</t>
    
    <!-- Settings Menu -->
    <t id="30500">GalaxyTrader MK1 Settings</t>
    <t id="30501">Station Trader Defaults</t>
    <t id="30502">Default Max Sell Distance</t>
    <t id="30503">Default Sell Cargo Fill Target</t>
    <t id="30504">Default Ignore Trade Rules</t>
    <t id="30505">Default Backtrack Tolerance</t>
    <t id="30506">Wait Time When No Trades Found</t>
    <t id="30507">Default Buy Cargo Fill Target</t>

    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <!-- Galaxy-Miner                               -->
    <!-- ID Range: 31000–31999                      -->
    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <t id="31002">Galaxy-Miner</t>
    <t id="31102">Autonomous mining with station supply and XP progression</t>
    <t id="31010">Home Station</t>
    <t id="31110">Station to mine for and deliver to (mutually exclusive with Home Sector)</t>
    <t id="31011">Home Sector</t>
    <t id="31111">Sector to operate in; used when no Home Station is set</t>
    <t id="31012">Resource Basket</t>
    <t id="31112">Wares to mine; empty follows station demand resolution</t>
    <t id="31013">Target Stations</t>
    <t id="31113">Optional station filter for deliveries; empty derives from home context</t>
    <t id="31014">Overflow Threshold %</t>
    <t id="31114">Stations at or above this storage percent are treated as full</t>
    <t id="31015">Allow Overflow Sell to Others</t>
    <t id="31115">When enabled and primary targets are full, sell to other faction stations</t>
    <t id="31016">Assign to Station</t>
    <t id="31116">Assign ship as mining subordinate of Home Station when applicable</t>
    <t id="31017">Stay at Home</t>
    <t id="31117">Restrict mining/selling to home area except overflow fallback runs</t>
    <t id="31018">Auto Deploy Resource Probes</t>
    <t id="31118">Hybrid scout-and-mine: opportunistically deploys probes in mining sectors, collects stale probes from sectors that no longer match the basket, and — when find_closest_resource turns up nothing because the basket asteroids are undiscovered — flies to a sector that has the asteroid type, runs the vanilla resource-scout sweep there to drop a probe, then resumes normal mining the next loop iteration. The Probe Stock Target slider controls per-trip restock amount when the ship runs out.</t>
    <t id="31019">Max Gather Distance</t>
    <t id="31119">Maximum gate distance for gathering (0 uses pilot/commander skill cap)</t>
    <t id="31020">Max Sell Distance</t>
    <t id="31120">Maximum gate distance for selling (0 uses pilot/commander skill cap)</t>
    <t id="31021">Fleet Balancing</t>
    <t id="31121">Enable deterministic intent coordination to reduce station overflow</t>
    <t id="31022">Demand Recheck Interval</t>
    <t id="31122">How often miner demand/switch evaluation runs</t>
    <t id="31023">Critical Demand Delta</t>
    <t id="31123">Minimum urgency delta required to switch active mining ware</t>
    <t id="31024">Min Switch Cooldown</t>
    <t id="31124">Minimum time between two ware switches for this ship</t>
    <t id="31025">Min Cargo Commit %</t>
    <t id="31125">If cargo fill is above this, ship prefers finishing current delivery before switch</t>
    <t id="31026">Hard Emergency Delta</t>
    <t id="31126">Urgency delta that allows immediate switch despite cargo commit threshold</t>
    <t id="31027">Notification Level</t>
    <t id="31127">Notification level: 0=Quiet, 1=Normal, 2=Verbose</t>
    <t id="31028">Player Stations Only</t>
    <t id="31128">When enabled, only player-owned stations are considered as demand targets.</t>
    <t id="31029">Probe Stock Target</t>
    <t id="31129">Number of resource probes the miner buys per restock trip. The buy is triggered ONLY when the ship has run out of probes (count = 0), not on every deploy — that way the miner runs through its full probe load between supply runs instead of detouring after each deployment. Capped by the ship's total deployable capacity (shared with satellites/mines/etc); a slider value larger than free deployable space gracefully degrades to "fill what fits". Only takes effect when Auto Deploy Resource Probes is enabled — the same setting also drives opportunistic probe deployment in mining sectors and collection of stale probes (probes in sectors with no basket-relevant resources).</t>

    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <!-- GalaxyTrader MK4 — Supply Trader           -->
    <!-- ID Range: 32000–32999                      -->
    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <t id="32002">GalaxyTrader MK4 Supply</t>
    <t id="32102">Player station supply trader using GT cache/live search pipeline</t>
    <t id="32010">Coverage Distance</t>
    <t id="32110">Maximum gate distance from home for destination demand search</t>
    <t id="32011">Buy Distance</t>
    <t id="32111">Maximum gate distance from home for supplier search</t>
    <t id="32012">Serve Home Only</t>
    <t id="32112">When enabled, only home station demand is served</t>
    <t id="32013">Build Stations Only</t>
    <t id="32113">When enabled, only build storage demand is served</t>
    <t id="32014">Buy from Player</t>
    <t id="32114">Allow sourcing wares from player-owned suppliers</t>
    <t id="32015">Buy from Faction</t>
    <t id="32115">Allow sourcing wares from non-player faction suppliers</t>
    <t id="32016">Allow Resources</t>
    <t id="32116">Include resource wares in demand matching</t>
    <t id="32017">Allow Intermediates</t>
    <t id="32117">Include intermediate wares in demand matching</t>
    <t id="32018">Allow Products</t>
    <t id="32118">Include product wares in demand matching</t>
    <t id="32019">Allow Tradewares</t>
    <t id="32119">Include tradeware wares in demand matching</t>

    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <!-- GalaxyTrader MK2 — Distribution Trader     -->
    <!-- ID Range: 20000–20999                      -->
    <!-- ========================================== -->
    <t id="20002">GalaxyTrader MK2</t>
    <t id="20102">Warehouse distribution with storage threshold management</t>
    <t id="20010">Source Stations</t>
    <t id="20011">Destination Stations</t>
    <t id="20012">Min Storage %</t>
    <t id="20013">Static Storage %</t>
    <t id="20014">Max Storage %</t>
    <t id="20015">Ware Filter</t>
    <t id="20016">Bidirectional Mode</t>
    <t id="20017">Home Station (optional)</t>
    <t id="20018">Max Distance</t>
    <t id="20019">Cycle Wait Time</t>
    <t id="20030">Allow Low Volume</t>
    <t id="20031">Low Volume Floor %</t>
    <t id="20110">List of source stations to distribute wares from</t>
    <t id="20111">List of destination stations/warehouses to distribute wares to</t>
    <t id="20112">Destination urgency threshold: stations below this storage % receive priority deliveries</t>
    <t id="20113">Source minimum threshold: source must have more than this % to distribute at all</t>
    <t id="20114">Source overflow threshold: above this % source distributes even to non-urgent destinations</t>
    <t id="20115">Optional ware filter; leave empty to distribute all wares from the source</t>
    <t id="20116">Enable return-trip collection from destinations back to source when destinations have excess</t>
    <t id="20117">Optional home station for assignment. If empty, ship remains unassigned to stations.</t>
    <t id="20118">Maximum gate distance between source and destinations (0 = unlimited)</t>
    <t id="20119">Time to wait between distribution cycles</t>
    <t id="20130">Allow smaller urgency-aware delivery chunks below normal minimum cargo fill.</t>
    <t id="20131">Minimum cargo fill % used when low-volume mode is enabled.</t>
    <t id="20200">Distributing %1 %2 from %3 to %4</t>
    <t id="20201">Return trip: collecting %1 %2 from %3 to %4</t>
    <t id="20202">No distribution needed — all destinations adequately supplied</t>
    <t id="20203">Source station %1 destroyed — distribution order cancelled</t>
    <t id="20204">All destination stations invalid — distribution order cancelled</t>
    <t id="20500">GalaxyTrader MK2 - Global Settings</t>
    <t id="20501">MK2 Distribution Defaults</t>
    <t id="20510">Default Min Storage %</t>
    <t id="20511">Default Static Storage %</t>
    <t id="20512">Default Max Storage %</t>
    <t id="20513">Default Cycle Wait (s)</t>
    <t id="20514">Minimum Cargo Fill %</t>
    <t id="20520">Notification Verbosity</t>
    <t id="20521">Debug Level</t>
    
  </page>
  

  
</language> 

